

# **SUMIT SHARMA**

Backend Developer

### 9125479651

sumitsharma37712@gmai.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sumit-sharma-57303a230

Chandan Nagar Colony, Ghazipur (233001), U.P.

### **EDUCATION**

### Diploma In Computer Science

Tathagat Gautam Buddha Government Polytechnic Sirsiya Shravasti

2019 - 2022

**Intermediate** 

M.A.H. Inter College, Ghazipur 2018-2019

### **SKILLS**

HTML NodeJs
CSS PHP

JavaScript MongoDB BootStrap MySQL

Tailwind CSS WordPress

ReactJs

ExpressJs

### LANGUAGE

English

Hindi

### Summary

Talented Software Developer equipped with great coding, debugging and project management abilities. Accomplishes project goals consistently with elegant, scable code. Works great with learn members under Agile and Scrum frameworks.

Backend Developer with deep code experience in Nodejs and PHP. Mentors and coaches junior developers in architecture and project management. Hardworking with excellent communication and collaboration skills.

# **Experience**

Apr 2023- Present Boolean ai Pvt. Ltd. I Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

#### **Backend Developer**

Worked closely with business stakeholders to understand requirements and design solutions that meet their needs. Here Company, Developed highly interactive and customized all APIs using NodeJs and MongoDB. Created a website for static and dynamic all website design using HTML,CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS and Bootstrap.

08/2022-02/2023 Softpro India Pvt. Ltd. Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

### **Apprenticeship Traning**

I am a trainee for a softpro India i a training Center which I learn and thought full Stack technologies and some skills.

## **Projects**

- 1. Pre Reporting Portal
- 2. Attendance Management System
- 3. Boolean ai
- 4. Chat Applications